Dr. Stephen Corwin Cameron Park Zoo records, Inclusive: 1965-2015, undated, Bulk: 1982-1995
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Dr. Stephen Corwin Cameron Park Zoo records
Inclusive: 1965-2015, undated, Bulk: 1982-1995
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
4037
Corwin, Stephen
15 document boxes
The Dr. Stephen Corwin Cameron Park Zoo records document the efforts of the Central Texas Zoological and Botanical Society to move the Central Texas Zoological Park to Cameron Park and the transitional period during this move, as well as the formative years of the Cameron Park Zoo and the Cameron Park Zoological Society. This collection shows the extensive efforts made to build a natural habitat zoo amongst an urban environment.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
In 1955 a few wildlife enthusiasts produced an exhibit of native Texas animals for display at the Heart O’ Texas Fair in Waco, Texas. The exhibit garnered so much attention that by the following year the Central Texas Zoological and Botanical Society had formed. The Society worked to raise funds for the construction of a Zoological Park in the Waco area. Though the Society considered Cameron Park as a potential site for the zoo, ultimately, the Central Texas Zoological Park opened on a ten-acre site near the Madison Cooper Municipal Airport.
The zoo relied mainly on volunteers to run the zoo and raise funds to cover maintenance. However, the zoo experienced frequent financial troubles and by 1977 the City of Waco took over ownership with the Society operating as boosters. Even with city support, the zoo continued to experience financial difficulties and requested the use of tax funds to continue operating. Soon after the change in ownership, the Society began discussions to build a natural habitat zoo located in Cameron Park, which would replace the outdated cages at the airport location.
Dr. Stephen Corwin, a urologist in Waco and long-time member of the Central Texas Zoological Society and former Chairman of the Zoo Board of Directors, initiated efforts to garner support for the zoo move. He presided as Chairman of the Zoo Relocation Committee for the Cameron Park Zoological Society, the new iteration of the Central Texas Zoological Society. Dr. Corwin saw his work come to fruition when, in 1983, the citizens of Waco passed a bond election held in support of the zoo relocation. The new Cameron Park Zoo, located on fifty-two acres of land, opened in the summer of 1993. Since its opening, the zoo has continued building and improving exhibits. Today, the zoo operates as a recreational and educational resource for all and plays a role in supporting wildlife conservation and research.
Scope and Content
This Collection begins in 1965 and ends in 2015. The collection documents the development, administration, publicity, and fundraising of the Cameron Park Zoo. These records include copies of the master plan for the zoo, plans for exhibit development, correspondence related to building the zoo, marketing plans, newspapers, grant applications, and information concerning donations. The collection also contains research materials concerning the operation of non-profit organizations and the activities of other zoos across the United States, administrative papers and news clippings for the Central Texas Zoological Park, the Central Texas Zoological and Botanical Society and the Cameron Park Zoological Society, and early photographs of the Cameron Park Zoo and Society members. In addition, the collection includes personal papers and correspondence of Dr. Stephen Corwin. The bulk of this collection covers the time period from 1982 to 1995. The majority of the materials relate to the development of the Cameron Park Zoo, from the initial decision to move the zoo from its original site through the early years of the zoo in Cameron Park. Most of the records reflect Dr. Stephen Corwin’s involvement with both iterations of the Zoological Societies and Zoological Parks.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, materials were foldered, loose and placed inside storage boxes. Items had no original order.
This collection is arranged into eight series: I. Administration, II. Marketing and Publicity, III. Financial Development, IV. Central Texas Zoological Park, V. Research Materials, VI. Waco Zoological Societies, VII. Dr. Stephen Corwin, and VIII. Media.
All folders have been arranged alphabetically within each series. Some items have been removed and placed in oversize document storage.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 4037. Acquired 2017-07-24
Related Resources
Related references
“City Approves Zoo Site.” The Waco Citizen, 1982 January 29. Accessed via newspapers.com. Accessed on 2019 May 8.
“County Passes Buck on Zoo Proposal to Attorney General.” The Waco Citizen, 1979 September 11. Accessed via newspapers.com. Accessed on 2019 May 8.
Interview of Stephen H. Corwin by Skylar Ray. McLennan County Medical Society 150th Anniversary, 2015 October 19. Transcript, Baylor University Institute for Oral History, Waco, Texas.
Miller, Sarah. “Cameron Park Zoo.” Waco History. Accessed on 2019 May 8.
“Police Sell and Buy Guns.” The Waco Citizen, 1977 November 18. Accessed via newspapers.com. Accessed on 2019 May 8.
“Site Proposed for Location of Waco Zoo.” The Waco News-Tribune, 1956 July 7. Accessed via newspapers.com. Accessed on 2019 May 8.
“Zoo Reaches Goal.” The Waco Citizen, 1976 July 16. Accessed via newspapers.com. Accessed on 2019 May 8.
“Zoo Vote Approved.” The Waco Citizen, 1983 July 29. Accessed via newspapers.com. Accessed on 2019 May 8.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Cameron Park Zoo.; Cameron Park Zoological and Botanical Society, Inc.; Central Texas Zoo.
Subjects
650 \0 Zoos--Design and constructionDLTexas--Waco.; Central Texas Zoological & Botanical Society.; Nonprofit organizations -- Finance.; Nonprofit organizations -- Marketing.; Zoos -- Planning -- Texas -- Waco.; Zoos -- Texas -- Waco.
Genres
Business correspondence.; Financial records.; Financial statements.; Negatives (Photographs); Newspapers.; Personal correspondence.; Photographs.; Proposals.; Records (Documents); Slides (photographs)
- Administration, 1980-2012, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains administrative documents related to the Cameron Park Zoo, including master plans for the construction of the zoo, contractor bids, professional correspondence, exhibit planning, business contracts, financial expenses, and animal acquisitions. The majority of the documents relate to the planning of the zoo.
  - Annual Report, 2005-2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aquarium Wing, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Asian Forest Expansion, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Attendance Statistics, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board Meetings, 1992-1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Budget and Expenditures, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Concessions, 1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1980-2000, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2), 1980-2000, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Covered Stage Contact, 2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Development Master Plan (1 of 2), 1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Development Master Plan (2 of 2), 1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Director of Development, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Director’s Activity Report, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Design Consortium, LTD., (1 of 2), 1990-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Design Consortium, LTD., (2 of 2), 1990-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Education Department, 2005, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Environmental Concerns, Inc., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Executive Summary, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Exhibit Updates, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Expansion Project, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Financial Statements, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Gift Shop, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Herpetarium Design Concept, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Maps, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Member Survey, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Memorandums, 1992-2004 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Memorandum of Agreement for Management and Operation Services for the Cameron Park Zoo, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Position Descriptions, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Programming, 1992, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Stationary, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Superintendent Interview Questionnaire, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Superintendent Selection Advisory Committee Resource Notebook (1 of 2), 1994 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Superintendent Selection Advisory Committee Resource Notebook (2 of 2), 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Visitor Concerns, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Zoo Commission Information and Orientation Material, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Zoo Director Applications (1 of 3), 1999 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Zoo Director Applications (2 of 3), 1999 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Zoo Director Applications (3 of 3), 1999 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Zoo Fact Sheet, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Zoo Trackers, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Zoo Planning, Background Materials, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Zoo Planning, Background Materials, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Zoo Planning, Background Materials, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Zoo Planning, Bond Referendum, 1982-1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Zoo Planning, Cameron Park map, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Zoo Planning, Cameron Park Study Committee (1 of 2), 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Zoo Planning, Cameron Park Study Committee (2 of 2), 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Zoo Planning, City Council., 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Zoo Planninjg, Community Service Bureau, Inc., 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Zoo Planning, Construction Finances, 1982-1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Zoo Planning, Construction Reports, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Zoo Planning, Correspondence Regarding Zoo Odors, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Zoo Planning, Agnew Moyer Smith, Inc. (1 of 3), 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Zoo Planning, Agnew Moyer Smith, Inc. (2 of 3), 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Zoo Planning, Agnew Moyer Smith, Inc. (3 of 3), 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Zoo Planning, The Alosaun Company Inc., 1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Zoo Planning, Animal Acquisition, 1992, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Zoo Planning, Design Consortium LTD, 1989 (Box [1029] OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Zoo Planning, Design Consortium LTD., 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Zoo Planning, Design Proposal Request (1 of 3), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Zoo Planning, Design Proposal Request (2 of 3), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Zoo Planning, Design Proposal Request (3 of 3), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Zoo Planning, Design Team Interview Agenda, 1989 February 22 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Zoo Planning, Feasibility and Developmental Analysis, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Zoo Planning, Food and Gift Facilities Proposals (1 of 3), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Zoo Planning, Food and Gift Facilities Proposals (2 of 3), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Zoo Planning, Food and Gift Facilities Proposals (3 of 3), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Zoo Planning, Interlocal Cooperation Agreement, 1988-1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Zoo Planning, John W. Erwin General Contractor, Inc. (1 of 2), 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Zoo Planning, John W. Erwin General Contractor, Inc. (2 of 2), 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Zoo Planning, Maps, undated (Box [1029] OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Zoo Planning, Master Plan (1 of 5), 1981-1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Zoo Planning, Master Plan (2 of 5), 1981-1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Zoo Planning, Master Plan (3 of 5), 1981-1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Zoo Planning, Master Plan (4 of 5), 1981-1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Zoo Planning, Master Plan (5 of 5), 1981-1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Zoo Planning, Master Plan Billing Statements, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Zoo Planning Master Plan Committee, 1981-1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Zoo Planning, Master Plan Contributors, 1981, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Zoo Planning, Master Plan Draft (1 of 4), 1980-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Zoo Planning, Master Plan Draft (2 of 4), 1980-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Zoo Planning, Master Plan Draft (3 of 4), 1980-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Zoo Planning, Master Plan Draft (4 of 4), 1980-1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Zoo Planning, Membership Luncheon, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Zoo Planning, Multi-media Show Production Budget, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Zoo Planning, the Portico Group Design Proposal (1 of 2), January 30, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Zoo Planning, the Portico Group Design Proposal (2 of 2), January 30, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Zoo Planning, Proposal Correspondence, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Zoo Planning, Raso-Greaves Design Proposal, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Zoo Planning, Survey of Zoos, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Zoo Planning, Task Force (1 of 2), 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Zoo Planning, Task Force (2 of 2), 1987-1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Zoo Planning, United States Zoo Budgets, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Zoo Planning, Zoo Development Committee, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Zoo Planning, Zoo Planning Associates, Inc. (1 of 2), 1981-1989, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Zoo Planning, Zoo Planning Associates, Inc. (2 of 2), 1981-1989, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Zoo Planning, Zoo Planning Associates, Inc. Maps (1 of 2), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Zoo Planning, Zoo Planning Associates, Inc. Maps (2 of 2), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Zoo Planning, Zoo Relocation Committee (1 of 2), 1980-1988, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Zoo Planning, Zoo Relocation Committee (2 of 2), 1980-1988, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Marketing and Publicity, 1979-2009, undated; 2
  This series contains documents related to the marketing strategy of the Cameron Park Zoo, including marketing plans, various bond campaigns, pamphlets, public speeches, and zoo publications. This series also contains items related to zoo publicity, such as newspaper articles about the zoo.
  - Bond Campaigns (1 of 2), 1983-2000 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Bond Campaigns (2 of 2), 1983-2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Brazos River Country, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Brochures, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Cowley & Pieratt, Incorporated, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Dewall Burks Pollei Advertising, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Groundbreaking Ceremony, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Letter to the Editor, 2000, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Magazines, 1986-1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Marketing Plan, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Multimedia Presentations, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, 1979-2000 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Newspapers (1 of 8), 1979-2009 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Newspapers (2 of 8), 1979-2009 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Newspapers (3 of 8), 1979-2009 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Newspapers (4 of 8), 1979-2009 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Newspapers (5 of 8), 1979-2009 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Newspapers (6 of 8), 1979-2009 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Newspapers (7 of 8), 1979-2009 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers (8 of 8), 1979-2009 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers (1 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Newspapers (2 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Mock-Up, circa 1983 (Box [1029] OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Park Zoo Informational Booklet, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Poll Data, 1979-1988 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Public Statements, 1981-2004, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Recruitment Packets, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Site Tours, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Spaeth Communications, Inc., 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Sphar Productions, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Zoo Files, 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Zoo Opening, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Zoo Relocation Support, 1983, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Zoobilee, 1993-1997 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Financial Development, 1975-2000, undated; 3
  This series contains items related to the financial development of the zoo, including grant applications, recruitment of donors, donor information, donation amounts, lists of potential donors and grants, and documents related to donor recognition.
  - Activity Reports, 1995-1996, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - The Alosaun Company, Inc., 1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Animal Donations, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Annual Fund Donation Requests, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Bond Campaigns (1 of 3), 1982-2000, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Bond Campaigns (2 of 3), 1982-2000, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Bond Campaigns (3 of 3), 1982-2000, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Capital Campaigns, 1988-1993, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Charitable Support, 1992, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - The Contributor’s Review Committee of Greater Waco, 1980-1983, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Development Planning, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Donations, 1982-1995, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Donor Recognition, 1993, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Exhibit Funding, 1992, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Federal Funding to Zoos, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Foundational Support, 1977-1999, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Fundraising Costs, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Grants, 1991, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - H&B Construction, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - James W. Jollier Memorial, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Junior League, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Legal Agreements-Zoo Tax, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Living Centers of America, Inc., 1993 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Marketplace Articles, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Municipal Zoo, 1965-1980 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Political Contributions, 1988-1993 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Potential Funding Sources, 1979-1996, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Texas Parks and Wildlife, 1975-1977, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Waco Comprehensive Plan 2000, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Waco Jaycees, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Waco Sesquicentennial Commission, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Central Texas Zoological Park, 1974-1991, undated; 4
  This series contains documents related to the Central Texas Zoological Park, the predecessor of the Cameron Park Zoo. Materials include administrative documents, professional correspondence, newspaper articles, and zoo publications.
  - Accreditation, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Adopt an Animal, 1975-1977, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Advisory Board, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Annual Report, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Bald Eagle Research and Preservation Project, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Board of Directors, 1977-1984, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Braz Walker Aquarium and Library, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Brochures, 1981-1991, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Community Development, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Complimentary Pass, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Cooper Foundation, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1983, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Development Strategies, 1989-1990, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Director’s Report, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Docents, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Donations, 1978, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Donor Relations, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Employment, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Fact Sheets, 1987, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Financial Documents, 1977-1986 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Friends of the Zoo Society, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Granes Graphics, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Grant Applications (1 of 3), 1978-1979, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Grant Applications (2 of 3), 1978-1979, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Grant Applications (3 of 3), 1978-1979, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Joint Zoo Development, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Master Plan, 1965-1979, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - McClennan County Commissioners, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Media Album, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Municipal Zoo (1 of 2), 1976-1982, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Municipal Zoo (2 of 2), 1976-1982, undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Newsletters (1 of 2), 1976-1989, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters (2 of 2), 1976-1989, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers (1 of 2), circa 1976-1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers (2 of 2), circa 1976-1991 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Newspapers, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Poems, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Poster, undated (Box [1029] OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Public Relations, 1974-1983, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Tax Exempt Status, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Tax Referendum, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - United States Department of Agriculture, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Visitor Research, 1981-1985 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Zoo Board, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Zoo Information, 1976-1982, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Zoo Wage and Fringe Benefit Surveys, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Research Materials, 1976-1998, undated; 5
  This series contains research materials, including articles about operating non-profit organizations, how to write professionally, and creating financial development strategies, as well as publications from other zoos and professional organizations.
  - Age Report, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - American Association of Zoological Parks and Aquariums (1 of 2), 1976-1977, 1991-1993, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - American Association of Zoological Parks and Aquariums (2 of 2), 1976-1977, 1991-1993, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Boardroom Essays, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Brownsville, Texas, and Valley Zoological Society Operational Agreement, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Citizen Participation, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Example Budget, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Formula for Getting a Bond Issue Approved, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Fundraising, 1994, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Gift Shops, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Impact of the Travel Industry on Waco, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - It’s All Happening at the Zoo, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Magazine Articles, 1981-1983, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Marketing in Zoos, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - The Marketplace Perspective, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Membership Applications, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, 1977-1981 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Newspapers, 1979-1993, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Pamphlets, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Parks and Recreation Department, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Planned Giving Principles, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Planning Study for the City of Waco’s Expanded Visitor Marketing Program, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Print Materials Guidelines, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Privatization of Zoos, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Role of Non-Profit Boards, 1983-1992 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Souvenirs, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Texas Parks and Wildlife, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Waco Economy, circa 1980 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - “Waco Perpetual Growth Foundation”, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Waco Visitors Bureau, 1987 (Box [1029] OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Waco Visitors Bureau (1 of 2), 1987-1989, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Waco Visitors Bureau (2 of 2), 1987-1989, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)